Joseph Arthur Moore Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Joseph Arthur Moore Papers 1910-1927
MSS33340
Moore, Joseph Arthur, 1879-1937
50 items
15 containers
3 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Publisher and newspaperman. Correspondence between Moore and William Randolph Hearst concerning newspaper operations and policy, local and national politics, and Hearst’s magazine and motion picture interests. Also includes printed matter and correspondence with Arthur Brisbane, Robert W. Chambers, Millicent Wilson Hearst, and Ray Long.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Brisbane, Arthur, 1864-1936--Correspondence.; Chambers, Robert W. (Robert William), 1865-1933--Correspondence.; Hearst, Millicent Willson, 1882-1974--Correspondence.; Hearst, William Randolph, 1863-1951--Correspondence.; Hearst, William Randolph, 1863-1951.; Long, Ray, 1878-1935--Correspondence.; Moore, Joseph Arthur, 1879-1937.
Subjects
American newspapers.; American periodicals.; Motion pictures.
Places
United States--Politics and government--1901-1953.
Occupations
Newspapermen.; Publishers.
Provenance
The papers of Joseph Arthur Moore, publisher and newspaperman, were given to the Library of Congress by his son, Joseph Arthur Moore, Jr., in 1955.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Joseph Arthur Moore are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Joseph Arthur Moore (1879-1937) span the years 1910-1927 and consist of bound and unbound correspondence and printed matter relating to Moore’s relationship with publisher William Randolph Hearst.
The correspondence spans the years 1915-1927 and consists principally of letters, telegrams, and memoranda between Moore and Hearst concerning newspaper operations and policy, local and national politics, and Hearst’s magazine and motion picture interests. It also includes correspondence with Arthur Brisbane, Robert W. Chambers, Millicent Hearst, and Ray Long. The printed matter consists of articles on Hearst and other miscellaneous items.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
Container List
- Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Bound (Box 1)
    - 1915, Feb. 14-1918, May 25 (Box 1)
    - 1918, May 27-1919, June 21 (Box 2)
    - 1919, June- Dec. 30 (Box 3)
    - 1920, Jan. 2-1920, Aug. 20 (Box 4)
    - 1920, Aug. 21-1921, Feb. 2 (Box 5)
    - 1921, Feb. 3-1921, Sept. 19 (Box 6)
    - 1921, Sept. 20-1922, Apr. 29 (Box 7)
    - 1922, May 3-1923, Jan. 3 (Box 8)
    - 1923, Jan. 4-1923, Nov. 14 (Box 9)
    - 1923, Nov. 15-1924, July 21 (Box 10)
    - 1924, July 22-1925, Feb. 26 (Box 11)
    - 1925, Feb. 28-May 20 (Box 12)
    - 1925, May 21-Sept. 18 (Box 13)
    - 1925, Sept. 19-1927, Aug. 21 (Box 14)
  - Unbound, 1920-1924 (Box 15)
- Printed matter, 1910-1924, undated, (2 folders) (Box 15)